<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sir Thomas Grosvenor's case, in answer to the petition of William Monson and William Thompson esqs and others, in order to avoid the said Sir Thomas his priviledge as a member of the honourable House of Commons in Parliament.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1699-1700?</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 6 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A60306</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing S3899</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R222397</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99833575</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99833575</idno>
            <idno type="VID">38052</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A60306)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 38052)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2217:10)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Sir Thomas Grosvenor's case, in answer to the petition of William Monson and William Thompson esqs and others, in order to avoid the said Sir Thomas his priviledge as a member of the honourable House of Commons in Parliament.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1699-1700]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing.</note>
                  <note>With a docket title.</note>
                  <note>The petition that this item is in answer to not found.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Lincoln's Inn Library, London.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Grosvenor, Thomas, --  Sir, 1655 or 6-1700 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Monson, William, fl. 1700 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Thompson, William, fl. 1700 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-01</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-01</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-03</date>
            <label>Elspeth Healey</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-10</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Rekeyed and resubmitted</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="115" facs="tcp:38052:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 10 -->
            <head>Sir <hi>Thomas Groſvenor</hi>'s <hi>CASE,</hi> in Anſwer to the Petition of <hi>William Monſon</hi> and <hi>William Thompſon</hi> 
               <abbr>Eſqs</abbr> and others, in order to avoid the ſaid Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> his Priviledge as a Member of the Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nourable <hi>Houſe of Commons</hi> in Parliament.</head>
            <p>THE ſaid Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> doth admit, that he did Demiſe the Mines in the ſaid Petition mentioned, unto <hi>Phineas Bowles</hi> and <hi>John Blunt,</hi> as in the Petition is ſet forth; and Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> did immediately deliver all the Ground men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned therein; with which the Petitioners did reſt ſatisfied for theſe Six years and upwards, without laying any further Claim.</p>
            <p>Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> does not detain any of their Rights, or diſturb them in their Poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſions, for the Place in queſtion was never in the poffeſſion of the Petitioners, or ever Lett by the Leaſe to <hi>Bowles</hi> and <hi>Blunt,</hi> but the Place was before Leaſed and granted to Mr. <hi>Roger Moſtyn,</hi> and Mr. <hi>Williams,</hi> who have ſo Sworn it, in their Anſwers to the Petitioners Bill in <hi>Chancery;</hi> and the Ground was then, and has ever ſince continued in their poſſeſſion, as Sir <hi>Thomas</hi>'s Tenants, and Workmen.</p>
            <p>But Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> doth deny, and ſo in his Anſwer in <hi>Chancery</hi> to the Petitioners ſaid Bill, hath denied, that he was privy or conſenting to the Aſſignment of that Leaſe to the ſaid Petitioners; and the ſaid Sir <hi>Thomas,</hi> by his ſaid Anſwer, hath ſet forth, That the ſaid Leſſees, and the Petitioners under them, had forfeited the ſaid Leaſe by Misfeazances, and not Working the ſaid Mines as they ought to have done, and yet notwithſtanding have enjoyed the benefit thereof, and that the ſaid Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> offered to wave the ſaid Forfeiture, and to allow the ſaid Leaſe upon moderate Terms, in the Anſwer ſet forth, which they refuſed or neglected to do; And by his Anſwer de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies expresſly, as the truth is, that he, or any claiming under him, had in any fort en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tred upon, or diſturbed the ſaid Leſſees of the benefit of the Mines ſo demiſed, to the beſt of his knowledge: And that the Petitioners had combined with one <hi>Davies,</hi> and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers, to defeat his Title to the ſaid Mines by foul and indirect Practices, which <hi>Davies</hi> obtained a Leaſe thereof behind Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> his back, and without notice to Sir <hi>Thomas,</hi> and entred thereupon by colour thereof, which Mines are Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> his Inheritance, the ſaid <hi>Davies</hi> pretending that Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> held them by Uſurpation, and in wrong of the Crown, whereby Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> was greatly vexed and diſturbed, and at this day the ſaid <hi>Davies</hi> pretends to find defects in Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> his Grant of the Mines, and thereby to let in the ſaid Leaſe.</p>
            <p>And Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> doth deny, that he Ordered the Petitioners Workmen to be beaten off the Work by violence, or to be threatned to be, or that he knows that one of them was buried alive in the Pit, as the Petitioners have falſely and ſcandalouſly ſuggeſted in the Caſe by them Printed and Publiſhed, and actually delivered to many Members of this Honourable Houſe; Which Suggeſtions tend to the great Defamation and Reproach of the ſaid Sir <hi>Thomas,</hi> who, as he is a Member of this Honourable Houſe, humbly Prays, that this Honourable Houſe will be pleaſed to take the ſame into Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſideration, and do him Right therein, the rather, for that if the ſame Matter had been true, yet was it altogether unneceſſarily inſerted in the ſaid Caſe as to the Matter prayed by the Petitioners ſaid Petition, and therefore could be deſigned only to render the ſaid Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> Obnoxious, and even Odious.</p>
            <p>And it doth appear by the Petitioners own ſhewing in their ſaid Caſe, That Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> hath done no Violence or Injury in his own Perſon to the Petitioners, their Workmen or Works, and that as to ſuch other; Perſons as the Petitioners pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend have done them wrong, and they Indicted them, and had the Liberty of the Law againſt them, and the ſaid Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> wholly left them to the Law.</p>
            <p>Sir <hi>Thomas Groſvenor</hi> denies to have ever waved his Priviledge, or hindred the Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>titioners in delivering their Petition laſt Seſſions, but after the Prorogation, pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuant to the General Order of the Houſe, did put in his Anſwer. 'Tis true he came to Dr.<hi>Newton,</hi> the Maſter in <hi>Chancery, November</hi> laſt, and told him his Sollicitor was out of Town, and he had none of his Papers, and produced to him the Vote of the Houſe, and did inſiſt on his Priviledge during the ſitting of the Houſe, but as ſoon as it was up, that he would appear with his Councel, and argue the Exceptions.</p>
            <p>And as to the Exceptions put in to the ſaid Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> his Anſwer in <hi>Chancery,</hi> as in the Petition) he ſaith, That his ſaid Anſwer is direct and full to all the neceſſary parts of the Petitioners Bill, as thereby may appear, and that the ſaid Exceptions are merely frivolous and impertinent, and deſigned only to Trouble and Perplex him, and tend to the Diſcompoſing and Retarding him in the Diſcharge of his Duty and Service of this Honourable Houſe: And therefore humbly Prayeth, That he may have his Priviledge allowed him according to the Vote and Standing Order of this Honourable Houſe of the 17th of <hi>April</hi> 1699.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
